Arash Pourhabibi-Zarandi

Computer Science PhD Candidate Swiss Federal Institute of Technology in Lausanne (EPFL)

CONTACT INFO

ADDRESS: EPFL IC IINFCOM PARSA, INJ 238, Station 14, 1015 Lausanne, Switzerland

PHONE: +41 21 693 13 79

EMAIL: arash.pourhabibi@epfl.ch WEBSITE: http://arash.pourhabibi.info

INTERESTS

I am broadly interested in the field of computer systems and interdisciplinary systems-level problems found in modern, large-scale datacenters, from cloud services to data stores and all the way down to server systems. By characterizing modern datacenter applications, I look for maximizing the compute density of server systems and minimizing their energy footprint through specialization of various system components and better system integration. My current focus is on the evasion of the RPC tax in datacenters through hardware-software co-design.

EDUCATION

2015-2021 (Expected)

Ph.D. in Computer & Communication Sciences

Swiss Federal Institue of Technology in Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland

Doctoral Research Assistant at PARSA lab under supervision of Prof. Babak FALSAFI

Thesis: Hardware-software Co-design to Evade the RPC Tax in Datacenters

Related Courses: Advanced Multiprocessor Architecture, Topics on Datacenter Design, Understanding Datacenter Software Dynamics

2013-2015

M.Sc. in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering)

Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran

Thesis: Design & Implementation of a Scheme for Big Data Processing on GPU

Advisor: Dr. Farshad Khunjush

Ranked First: Achieving the highest course GPA (19.84/20) among all M.Sc. students

Related Courses: Advanced OS, Advanced Computer Architecture, Multicore Programming, Parallel Algorithms, Grid Comput-

ing, Software Architecture, Text Mining

2009-2013

B.Sc. in Computer Engineering (Software Engineering)

Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran

Ranked First: Achieved the highest GPA in CS courses (18.88/20) among all B.Sc. students

WORK EXPERIENCE

CURRENT

Doctoral Research Assistant

SEP. 2015

PARSA Lab, EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland

Contributed to several research projects focused on hardware and software co-design for future generations of datacenter servers. Supervised junior students and summer interns. Member of the CloudSuite team, and part of the core team responsible for its 3rd release. Member of the Flexus simulator maintenance team, and part of the core team working on its new incarnation branded as QFlex.

2010-2013

Member of the IT Task Force

CS Department, Shiraz University, Iran

In charge of the maintenance of department's network infrastructure and IT services. Proposed and implemented new services for the department such as a CMS.

2011-2013

Freelance Java and iOS Developer

Involved in development of a payment switch system (in Java). Co-founded the Mobile Programming group at Shiraz University and developed a bill payment app for iPhone.

2010-2011

Intern at Shiraz University's CERT Center (ShirazAPA)

Involved in research and development of several security-related projects such a secure update manager.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, C/C++, Java, PThreads, OpenMP, CUDA, MPI

Operating Systems: macOS, Linux, Windows

Miscellaneous: Git, Docker, LaTeX, Shell Scripting, Agile Development

Basic Familiarity: Objective-C, Ruby, PHP, HTML, JavaScript

PUBLICATIONS & PATENTS

- 1. Cerebros: Evading the RPC Tax in Datacenters. A. Pourhabibi, M. Sutherland, A. Daglis, B. Falsafi. *To appear in Proceedings of the 54th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture, MICRO'21*, Athens, Greece, October 2021.
- 2. Equinox: Training (for Free) on a Custom Inference Accelerator. M. Drumond, L. Coulon, A. Pourhabibi, A. Yüzügüler, B. Falsafi, M. Jaggi. To appear in Proceedings of the 54th IEEE/ACM International Symposium on Microarchitecture, MICRO'21, Athens, Greece, October 2021.
- 3. Data Transformer Apparatus. A. Pourhabibi, S. Gupta, H. Kassir, M. Sutherland, Z. Tian, M. Drumond, B. Falsafi, C. Koch. *Patent (Pending)*, March 2021.
- 4. **Optimus Prime: Accelerating Data Transformation in Servers.** A. Pourhabibi, S. Gupta, H. Kassir, M. Sutherland, Z. Tian, M. Drumond, B. Falsafi, C. Koch. *In Proceedings of the 25th ACM International Conference on Architectural Support for Programming Languages and Operating Systems, ASPLOS'20*, Lausanne, Switzerland, March 2020.
- 5. Towards near-threshold server processors. A. Pahlevan, J. Picorel, A. P. Zarandi, D. Rossi, M. Zapater, A. Bartolini, P. G. Del Valle, D. Atienza, L. Benini, and B. Falsafi. *In Proceedings of the 2016 Conference on Design, Automation & Test in Europe (DATE)*, Dresden, Germany, March 2016.
- 6. The official Persian translation of "Engineering SaaS: An Agile Approach Using Cloud Computing" written by Armando Fox and David PATTERSON. *Currently under preparation*.

AWARDS & HONORS

DEC. 2018	Awarded the Teaching Assistant Award for teaching excellence		
	School of Computer & Communication Sciences (IC), EPFL, Lausanne, Switzerland		
SUMMER 2014	Ranked 2 nd at the first Iran Programming Skill Challenge (Java section)		
SUMINIER 2014	Held by Sharif University of Technology and Tehran University's Faculty of Entrepreneurship, Iran		
	There by sharif officersity of reclinology and remail officersity's ractity of Entrepreheurship, trail		
SEP. 2013	Honorary admission to the M.Sc. program without university entrance exam		
	Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran		
'			
June 2013	Awarded as the Best Undergraduate Student in Computer Engineering		
	Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran		
FEB. 2012	Nominated for the Best Mobile Application for SAHA (payment app for iPhone)		
	The First Iran Mobile Innovation Awards, held by Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran		

PROFESSIONAL & EXTRACURRICULAR SERVICES

ASPLOS 2020	Artifact Evaluation	on Committee Member
/\JI LOJ 2020	/ II that L valuation	on committee wiching

DEC. 2014 | Co-organizer of an Hour of Code Event

Organized a one-day workshop, participating in the Hour of Code program, for tens of high-school and middle-school students and taught them the basics of computer programming and algorithmic thinking.

2010-2014 | BreakTime In University (BTiU)

BTiU is a three-day annual conference consists of tens of parallel workshops held by a group of university students during the summer at Shiraz University. Hundreds of talented high-schoolers attend this event to learn more about various study majors, practice teamwork, life and social skills, and learn how to be creative and innovative. I had the chance to be a part of the organizing team for five years.

MAY 2012 | Member of Conference Organizing Committee

Internet and technical services assistant at the 16^{th} CSI International Symposiums on Computer Architecture & Digital Systems (CADS 2012) and Artificial Intelligence & Signal Processing (AISP 2012) held at Shiraz University, Shiraz, Iran.

LANGUAGES

PERSIAN: Native Proficiency

ENGLISH: Full Professional Proficiency FRENCH: Elementary Proficiency

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

2015-2021

CloudSuite

CloudSuite is a benchmark suite of cloud services. The benchmarks are based on real-world software stacks and represent real-world setups. It is one of the early benchmark suites that is representative of modern datacenter services and is included in Google's PerfKit Benchmarker. It has become an industry standard and been used to drive the design of modern datacenter-oriented CPUs, such as Cavium ThunderX. I have been a core member of the team responsible for the maintenance and the third release of CloudSuite, which is a major enhancement over prior releases both in benchmarks and infrastructure.

2016-2021

QFlex

The QFlex project targets quick, accurate, and flexible simulation of multi-node computer systems proceeding along four fronts: QEMU, a popular open-source full-system machine emulator, Flexus, a powerful and flexible simulation framework that enables detailed cycle-accurate simulation, SMARTS, which applies rigorous statistical sampling theory to reduce the simulation time while achieving high accuracy, and NS-3, a popular and flexible network simulation stack. I have been a member of the Flexus maintenance team and the team responsible for its new incarnation branded as QFlex.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

FALL 2019	Introduction to Multiprocessor Architecture		
FALL 2018	Assisted in redesigning the course: constructed a new syllabus and prepared course material including lecture slides,		
FALL 2017	exercises, programming assignments, and exams. Graded assignments and exams. Led weekly lab sessions and guided		
FALL 2016			
FALL 2010	students. EPFL		
SPRING 2020	System Oriented Programming		
SPRING 2019	Assisted in redesigning the course: constructed a new course project and weekly tasks for students. Created a grading		
	and feedback infrastructure for the weekly tasks, graded the final project and led weekly lab sessions. EPFL		
SPRING 2018	Systems for Data Science		
	Graded students' assignments, projects and exams, held lab sessions and gave guidance to students for their		
	projects. EPFL		
Spring 2017	Programming II (Using C++)		
31 KING 2017	Graded students' programming assignments, projects and exams. Led weekly lab sessions and gave guidance to stu-		
	dents. EPFL		
SPRING 2014	Grid Computing		
	Graded students' programming assignments and projects. Shiraz University		
SPRING 2014	Software Architecture		
	Graded students' programming assignments and projects. Shiraz University		
SPRING 2014	Database Laboratory		
SPRING 2013 Completely redesigned the course from scratch. Constructed the syllabus and prepared the course material			
	lab sessions, gave guidance to students and graded their assignments and projects. Shiraz University		
FALL 2013	GPU Programming		
TALL 2015	Prepared and graded students' programming assignments and projects, led weekly lab sessions and gave guidance to		
	students. Shiraz University		
	1		
SPRING 2013	Design & Implementation of Programming Languages		
	Prepared students' programming assignments and projects. Shiraz University		
FALL 2012	Fundamentals of Computer and Programming Using Python		
FALL 2010	Constructed the syllabus and prepared the course material (programming assignments, labs, and projects). Led weekly		
	lab sessions, gave guidance to students and graded their assignments and projects. Shiraz University		
Capital 2012	Dringiples of Dragonomaing Using C		
SPRING 2012	-		
SPRING 2011	Prepared and graded students' programming assignments and projects, led weekly lab sessions and gave guidance to		
	students. Shiraz University		
FALL 2011	Advanced Programming Using Java		
17122 2011	/		

Last Update: July 2021

students. | Shiraz University

Prepared and graded students' programming assignments and projects, led weekly lab sessions and gave guidance to